<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | Jianing Wang</title>
    <link>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/media/icon_hu61a5cda683b16e16ad250d48d66bc7bc_4894_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication-type/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Calibration of a Simulation Model of Opioid Use Disorder</title>
      <link>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication/madu-2022-preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication/madu-2022-preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulation models of opioid use disorder (OUD) aim at evaluating the impact of different treatment
strategies on population-level outcomes. Researching Effective Strategies to Prevent Opioid Death
(RESPOND) is a dynamic population state-transition model that simulates Massachusetts (MA)
OUD population synthesizing data from the MA Public Health Data Warehouse, published survey
studies, and randomized trials. We implement an empirical calibration approach to fit RESPOND to
multiple calibration targets, including yearly counts of fatal overdoses and detox admissions in
2013-2015, and 2015 OUD population counts in MA. We used capture-recapture analysis to
estimate the OUD population and to quantify uncertainty around calibration targets.
1 The empirical
calibration approach involves Latin hypercube sampling for a parameter search of the
multidimensional space, comprising demographics of “arrivals”, overdose rates, treatment
transition rates, and substance use transition probabilities. The algorithm accepts proposed
parameter values when the respective model outputs are “close” to the observed calibration
targets based on uncertainty ranges of targets. Calibration provided an excellent fit to the model
calibration targets. The flexibility of the algorithm also allowed us to identify certain &amp;ldquo;questionable&amp;rdquo;
parts of the model structure and explore the underlying relationships between the model
parameters in an efficient manner. The calibrated model also provided a good fit to validation
targets: non-overdose related deaths, percentage of active OUDs, and all types of overdose counts
(fatal and non-fatal). In addition, the resulting set of values for the calibrated parameters will
inform the priors of a more comprehensive Bayesian calibration. The calibrated RESPOND model
will be employed to improve shared decision-making for OUD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example preprint / working paper</title>
      <link>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication0/sample-preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jianing-jenny-wang.github.io/publication0/sample-preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
